readtheory.org 2016-11-19

# Privacy Policy | ReadTheory

Privacy Policy

Our mission at ReadTheory.org is to teach every student to read and think critically.

ReadTheory.org is a proud supporter of the [Student Privacy Pledge](https://studentprivacypledge.org/) to safeguard student privacy. 

Last updated on September 8, 2016.

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Read Theory collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") of the website ("Site"). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Read Theory.

Personal identification information

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, register on the site, subscribe to the newsletter, and fill out a form on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, names and email addresses. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities. Users shall NOT be prompted to submit their personal, phone numbers, personal mailing addresses, dates of birth, or Social Security numbers (or foreign national identification numbers), nor will they be prompted to submit the phone numbers or mailing addresses of any educational institutions with which they may be associated. We also do not provide for the uploading of any manner of photographs, nor do we link accounts with any manner of third-party social media profiles.

Non-personal identification information

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

Web browser cookies

Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

How we use collected information

Read Theory may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes...

  * _To improve customer service_  
Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * _To personalize user experience_  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.
  * _To improve our Site_  
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.
  * _To send periodic emails_  
We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to our website. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. Registered teacher users will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site.

How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.

Sharing your personal information

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users' personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. We may use third party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.

Google Adsense

We may display advertisements to Users of our Site from time to time. Such advertisements are in compliance with [COPPA](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy), which applies to websites and services directed to children under the age of 13 and general audience sites or services with users known to be under the age of 13. Advertisements on our Site are non-targeted, whereas steps have been taken to disable interest-based advertising and remarketing ads for that content. This measure has been implemented on a Site-wide basis, meaning all advertisements present on the Site are COPPA compliant per the Google Adsense [child-directed treatment](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/3248194?hl=en) for advertisements. 

_Log Files_  
Like many other Web sites, www.readtheory.org makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

_Cookies and Web Beacons_  
www.readhtheory.org uses cookies to store information about visitors' preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

_DoubleClick DART Cookie_  
Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.readtheory.org.  
Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.readtheory.org and other sites on the Internet.  
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include...  
Google Adsense

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.readtheory.org send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.readtheory.org has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.readtheory.org's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites. 

US Education and Privacy Laws

Read Theory, LLC does not receive funding from the United States Department of Education and is as such not subject to the [FERPA](http://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html) Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act. Because the Site be utilized in full without any institutional licenses or exchange of payment, we do not stand in a contractual service agreement with any such USDE-funded institutions, nor do we act on such institutions' behalf, nor are we under the direct or indirect control of any such institution. We do not qualify as a "school official" for these purposes.

Statistics collected on student progress reports do not constitute "educational records" per FERPA. We do not provide guidelines, recommendations, or information of any kind for teachers or schools who wish to incorporate students' Read Theory activity into their official grades or other records. Any teacher who wishes to use the Site in this way does so at his or her own discretion and is responsible for protecting the privacy of any such data so utilized.

Progress reports are accessible only to the Users themselves by logging in to a password-protected Student Account. Progress reports may be visible to any password-protected Teacher Accounts to whom each User's account is linked. The User can remove himself from such an association with a Teacher Account at any time. We do not share or sell access to Users' progress reports with third parties.

Any parent or guardian of a minor who wishes to gain access to his or her child's progress report should submit their request in writing to support@readtheory.org.

In compliance with [COPPA](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/privacy-and-security/children%27s-privacy) Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we are required to obtain parental consent for all Users under 13 years of age. To this end, all Users signing up for new Student Accounts, as well as all Teacher Accounts creating Student Accounts on behalf of their students, shall review our [Parental Information Flyer](http://readtheory.org/static/pdf/parent_flyer.pdf) and keep this document for their records. Minors' continued use of the Site following parents' or guardians' review of our Parental Information Form is considered to constitute parental consent.

Any parent or guardian of an under-13 child whose account has already been created without parental consent or prior to the establishment of parental consent can petition to have the child's account deleted. Requests for account deletion should be submitted in writing to support@readtheory.org.

In the event of a data breach, we will notify Users within 72 hours. This notification may be delivered in the form of email or in general message posting in a prominent location on the Site. 

Changes to this privacy policy

Read Theory has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will post a notification on the main page of our Site. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications. 

Your acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy and Terms of Use. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes. 

Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at support@readtheory.org.
